Close
    
    #### Offices
    
    ##### North & Latin America

    ##### Europe & Africa

    ##### [Middle East](https://www.bain.com/offices/middle-east/)

    ##### Asia & Australia

    Close
    
    #### Select your region and language
    
    ##### Global
    
    * [Global (English)](https://www.bain.com/about/privacy/ "Global (English)")
    
    ##### North & Latin America
    
    * [Brazil (Português)](https://www.bain.com/pt-br/about/privacy/ "Brazil (Português)")
    * [Argentina (Español)](https://www.bain.com/es-ar/about/privacy/ "Argentina (Español)")
    * [Chile (Español)](https://www.bain.com/es-cl/about/privacy/ "Chile (Español)")
    * [Colombia (Español)](https://www.bain.com/es-co/about/privacy/ "Colombia (Español)")
    
    ##### Europe, Middle East, & Africa
    
    * [France (Français)](https://www.bain.com/fr/a-propos-de-bain/politique-de-confidentialite/ "France (Français)")
    * [DACH Region (Deutsch)](https://www.bain.com/de/ueber-uns/datenschutzhinweis/ "DACH Region (Deutsch)")
    * [Italy (Italiano)](https://www.bain.com/it/about-bain/privacy-policy/ "Italy (Italiano)")
    * [Spain (Español)](https://www.bain.com/es-es/about/privacy/ "Spain (Español)")
    * [Greece (Elliniká)](https://www.bain.com/el/about/privacy/ "Greece (Elliniká)")
    
    ##### Asia & Australia
    
    * [China (中文版)](http://www.bain.cn/ "China (中文版)")
    * [Korea (한국어)](https://www.bain.com/ko/about-bain/privacy/ "Korea (한국어)")
    * [Japan (日本語)](https://www.bain.com/ja/about-bain/privacy/ "Japan (日本語)")

    #### You have no saved content in your Red Folder.
    
    Bookmark content that interests you and it will be saved here for you to read or share later.

    Main menu
    
    #### [Industries](https://www.bain.com/industry-expertise/)

        Industries
        
        ##### [Energy & Natural Resources](https://www.bain.com/industry-expertise/energy-and-natural-resources/)

        Industries
        
        ##### [Financial Services](https://www.bain.com/industry-expertise/financial-services/)

        Industries
        
        ##### [Healthcare & Life Sciences](https://www.bain.com/industry-expertise/healthcare/)

        Industries
        
        ##### [Media & Entertainment](https://www.bain.com/industry-expertise/media-and-entertainment/)

        Industries
        
        ##### [Private Equity](https://www.bain.com/industry-expertise/private-equity/)

        Industries
        
        ##### [Retail](https://www.bain.com/industry-expertise/retail/)

        Industries
        
        ##### [Social & Public Sector](https://www.bain.com/industry-expertise/social-impact-consulting/)

        Industries
        
        ##### [Technology](https://www.bain.com/industry-expertise/technology/)

        Industries
        
        ##### [Telecommunications](https://www.bain.com/industry-expertise/telecommunications/)

        Industries
        
        ##### [Transportation](https://www.bain.com/industry-expertise/transportation/)

    Main menu
    
    #### [Consulting Services](https://www.bain.com/consulting-services/)

    Main menu
    
    #### [Insights](https://www.bain.com/insights/)

    ##### Featured topics

    Main menu
    
    #### [About](https://www.bain.com/about/)

    ##### Further: Our global responsibility

        About
        
        ##### [Diversity, Equity & Inclusion](https://www.bain.com/about/further/diversity-equity-inclusion/)

    Main menu
    
    #### [Careers](https://www.bain.com/careers/)

        Careers
        
        ##### [Work with Us](https://www.bain.com/careers/work-with-us/)

        Careers
        
        ##### [Life at Bain](https://www.bain.com/careers/life-at-bain/)

        Careers
        
        ##### [Hiring Process](https://www.bain.com/careers/hiring-process/)

    Main menu
    
    #### Offices

        Offices
        
        ##### North & Latin America

        Offices
        
        ##### Europe & Africa

        Offices
        
        ##### [Middle East](https://www.bain.com/offices/middle-east/)

        Offices
        
        ##### Asia & Australia

    Main menu
    
    #### Select your region and language

        Select your region and language
        
        ##### Global
        
        * [Global (English)](https://www.bain.com/about/privacy/ "Global (English)")

        Select your region and language
        
        ##### North & Latin America
        
        * [Brazil (Português)](https://www.bain.com/pt-br/about/privacy/ "Brazil (Português)")
        * [Argentina (Español)](https://www.bain.com/es-ar/about/privacy/ "Argentina (Español)")
        * [Chile (Español)](https://www.bain.com/es-cl/about/privacy/ "Chile (Español)")
        * [Colombia (Español)](https://www.bain.com/es-co/about/privacy/ "Colombia (Español)")

        Select your region and language
        
        ##### Europe, Middle East, & Africa
        
        * [France (Français)](https://www.bain.com/fr/a-propos-de-bain/politique-de-confidentialite/ "France (Français)")
        * [DACH Region (Deutsch)](https://www.bain.com/de/ueber-uns/datenschutzhinweis/ "DACH Region (Deutsch)")
        * [Italy (Italiano)](https://www.bain.com/it/about-bain/privacy-policy/ "Italy (Italiano)")
        * [Spain (Español)](https://www.bain.com/es-es/about/privacy/ "Spain (Español)")
        * [Greece (Elliniká)](https://www.bain.com/el/about/privacy/ "Greece (Elliniká)")

        Select your region and language
        
        ##### Asia & Australia
        
        * [China (中文版)](http://www.bain.cn/ "China (中文版)")
        * [Korea (한국어)](https://www.bain.com/ko/about-bain/privacy/ "Korea (한국어)")
        * [Japan (日本語)](https://www.bain.com/ja/about-bain/privacy/ "Japan (日本語)")

    Main menu

    #### You have no saved content in your Red Folder.
    
    Bookmark content that interests you and it will be saved here for you to read or share later.

    * #### [Industries](https://www.bain.com/industry-expertise/)

    * #### [Consulting Services](https://www.bain.com/consulting-services/)

    * #### [Insights](https://www.bain.com/insights/)

        ##### Featured topics

    * #### [About](https://www.bain.com/about/)

        ##### Further: Our global responsibility

Explore* 

Search insights, services, and experts" 

###### Popular Searches

###### Your Previous Searches

###### Recently Visited Pages

Content added to Red Folder

[Red Folder (0)](https://www.bain.com/about/red-folder-landing/) Close

Removed from Red Folder

[Red Folder (0)](https://www.bain.com/about/red-folder-landing/) Close

About Bain

Privacy Policy
==============

Privacy Policy
==============

Bain knows that your privacy is important to you and takes user privacy very seriously. We are committed to protecting your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

_Last updated on 9 November 2023_

This Privacy Policy applies to the website(s) and mobile applications (together, the "Sites") provided by Bain & Company Inc., a company headquartered in Boston, Massachusetts, USA, and/or the other companies of the Bain group ("Bain", “we”, “us”) who act as **[data controllers](#Data-controller)**\[1\] with respect to the personal data you share with Bain under this Policy.

The Sites include [www.bain.com](https://www.bain.com/) and additional websites or mobile applications produced and managed by Bain that link to this Policy.

Bain knows that your privacy is important to you and takes user privacy very seriously. We are committed to protecting your **[personal data](#personal-data)**\[2\] (i.e. any information you provide to us from which you can be identified) in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Bain reserves the right, at its sole discretion, to alter and update this Privacy Policy from time to time. We therefore invite you to review the current version of the Privacy Policy each time you return to our Sites.

Some terms are defined throughout this Policy. Simply click on the terms in bold to obtain their definition or refer to the definitions at the bottom of this Policy.

    **Bain might collect personal data from you such as your name, contact details, occupation, company or university affiliation, industry, region/country, relationship to Bain, reason for contacting Bain, topics you are interested in and any other information you choose to share. By browsing our Sites or sending us information, you explicitly consent to Bain processing your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Bain might use your personal data to fulfil your request, send you marketing communications, process your job application or manage your BeyondBain membership.**
    
    * * *
    
    Bain collects personal data from you when you request information from Bain and/or supply, information through the Sites, such as when you fill out a subscription form or consulting expertise inquiry, opt in to receive emails from Bain, agree to participate in surveys, join our Alumni community, BeyondBain, or apply for a role at Bain.
    
    Personal data we collect might include your name, e-mail address, title, occupation, company or university affiliation, industry, region/country, relationship to Bain, reason for contacting Bain, topics you are interested in, any other background information provided with an application and any other information contained in messages you send us.
    
    We might also collect information about how you use our Sites in accordance with our [Cookie Policy](https://www.bain.com/about/cookie-policy/). Please note that BeyondBain is governed by a separate Cookie Policy, which you can review [here](https://alumni.bain.com/login/cookie-policy/).
    
    By browsing our Sites and submitting this information to us, you explicitly agree to Bain using your personal data for the purposes and in the manner described in this Privacy Policy. Please do not send us any information you do not wish Bain to use.
    
    Bain will use your personal data to fulfil your request, provide you with the information you requested and/or send you marketing communications. If you have applied for a job at Bain, your data will be processed for the purposes of evaluating and processing your application and candidacy for the position to which you have applied. We may also use your information to analyze and improve our recruiting and onboarding processes as well as to communicate with you about Bain events and to send you publications that we think may be of interest to you. More detail can be found in the Job Applicants section.
    
    Bain may collect personal data and may disclose such information to third party service providers in aggregate for marketing and promotional purposes. However, in these situations, we do not disclose to these entities any information that could be used to personally identify you.
    
    If you register as a member on BeyondBain, your data will be processed for purposes including conducting alumni-specific mailings and surveys as well as maintaining and sharing marketing and career development contacts. Your data might also be visible to other BeyondBain members.
    
    You do not have to provide us with any personal data.  However, if you do not, we may be unable to handle your request or to provide you with the services you are requesting.
    
    Bain will keep your personal data for as long as needed to handle your request or for as long as we have a relationship with you. If you have applied for a role with Bain, Bain will keep your personal data associated with your application for a period of up to five years.
    
    Please note that Bain is not responsible for any information you may disclose publicly in any chat rooms, message boards, or similar web pages, including those hosted on or linked to our Sites. You should keep in mind that, whenever you publicly disclose information about yourself online (for example, via message boards or chat rooms), such information could be collected and used by people whom you do not know. In addition, certain message boards and similar user forums may display IP addresses along with the message poster's name and message. Bain bears no responsibility for any action or policies of any third parties who collect any information users may disclose on the message boards, chat areas or other user forums, if any, on the Sites.

    We may use cookies or other technology (“cookies”) to obtain certain types of information when you browse our Sites. You can find information about what data is collected and how it is used in our [Cookie Policy](https://www.bain.com/about/cookie-policy/).
    
    Please note that the use of cookies on BeyondBain is governed by a separate Cookie Policy, which you can review [here](https://alumni.bain.com/login/cookie-policy/).

    **We may share your personal data with other companies of the Bain group as well as with other third parties that might be located in a different country than your country of residence. Bain will not share or sell your data to any third party for their own use.**
    
    * * *
    
    We may share your personal data with others, such as:
    
    * other offices in the Bain group – for a complete list of our offices, please refer to the [Offices page of the bain.com website](http://www.bain.com/about/worldwide-offices/index.aspx);
    * carefully selected third party service providers, such as marketing service providers (if you have subscribed to our marketing communications), IT systems providers, recruitment service providers, background check providers, data cleansing providers or event organizers, so they can provide services to Bain;
    * our advisors;
    * other alumni members if you have chosen to take part in the Alumni network; and
    * law enforcement authorities or other government bodies when we are required to do so.
    
    Third parties, other than law enforcement authorities or government bodies, will only handle your personal data on behalf of Bain for the purposes described in this Policy. Bain will not sell or otherwise share your personal data with such third parties for their own use without your consent.
    
    The companies of the Bain group and other third parties we share your information with may be located in other countries, including countries that do not offer the same protection to your personal data as the country in which you reside. Where that is the case, Bain ensures that your personal data is protected by using appropriate legal mechanisms. If you reside in the European Union, such mechanisms include using contracts or wording approved by the European Commission (called “**[Standard Contractual Clauses](#standard-contractual-clauses)**”)\[3\].

    **Our Sites may contain links to third party websites that are governed by their own terms and privacy policies. Bain does not bear any liability and responsibility for the content or your use of these websites.**
    
    * * *
    
    The Sites may contain links to third party websites, including social network sites. Such websites are governed by their own terms of use and privacy policies, which you should review before browsing or submitting information to them. Bain is not responsible for the privacy practices of such websites. In addition, a link to a third party website does not mean that Bain endorses or accepts any responsibility for the content or the use of such website. Bain shall not bear any liability and responsibility for such content or for your use of these websites.

    **Bain has implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures in order to protect your personal data from loss, misuse, alteration, or destruction.**
    
    * * *
    
    Bain has implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures in order to protect your personal data from loss, misuse, alteration, or destruction. Such measures include **[anonymizing](#Anonymizing)** \[4\] or **[pseudonymizing](#pseudonymizing)**\[5\] data where possible. Authorized Bain personnel and third parties mentioned above will only have access to your personal data to the extent they need it to do their job or provide their services. Despite these precautions, however, Bain cannot guarantee that unauthorized persons will not obtain access to your information.

    **Depending on where you reside you might have the right to request access to, rectification or erasure of your personal data and to object to or ask for the restriction of the processing of your personal data. You might also have the right to withdraw your consent and request that we stop processing or delete your personal data.**
    
    **To exercise your rights, please submit your request using our [data subject request form](https://privacyportal-de.onetrust.com/webform/0ea9b6b4-9f39-441a-ad8c-05b2ae8f175c/aa3576c0-30dd-4d2e-b49b-5fdd7bfb9fe5).**
    
    * * *
    
    Depending on where you reside, you may be entitled to certain rights regarding the personal data Bain holds about you. For instance, you may have the right to request access to your information, obtain a copy of it as well as information about how we use it. You have the right to request that we correct incorrect, inaccurate or out-of-date information about you. You may also have the right to request that we stop processing your information and/or withdraw your consent to such processing and to ask us to delete your information.
    
    In the event that Bain holds personal data about you and you no longer wish for this data to be processed as described in this Policy, or if you wish to access, rectify, cancel or oppose such processing, please submit your request using our [data subject request form](https://privacyportal-de.onetrust.com/webform/0ea9b6b4-9f39-441a-ad8c-05b2ae8f175c/aa3576c0-30dd-4d2e-b49b-5fdd7bfb9fe5).
    
    If you receive marketing communications from Bain, you can opt out of receiving future emails from Bain or unsubscribe from participating in our programs through the "preferences" page, which is accessible in every marketing email you receive from Bain. You can also submit an opt-out request by using our [data subject request form](https://privacyportal-de.onetrust.com/webform/0ea9b6b4-9f39-441a-ad8c-05b2ae8f175c/aa3576c0-30dd-4d2e-b49b-5fdd7bfb9fe5).
    
    If you think we are handling your information unlawfully, we encourage you to get in touch with us using our [data subject request form](https://privacyportal-de.onetrust.com/webform/0ea9b6b4-9f39-441a-ad8c-05b2ae8f175c/aa3576c0-30dd-4d2e-b49b-5fdd7bfb9fe5). You may also have the right to lodge a complaint with your national supervisory authority.
    
    Please note that we will take reasonable steps to check your identity before handling your request.

    If you apply for a job at Bain, you will be asked to submit information to Bain such as your name, contact details, information about your education and work history and any other background information that might be relevant for your application or that you choose to share with Bain. If you do not provide this information to us, we might not be able to process your application.
    
    Bain will use this information to assess your application and candidacy for the position to which you have applied. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, this may include: (i) evaluating your skills and experience in relation to the qualification required for the job to which you have applied; and (ii) tracking feedback and interactions we have with you throughout the recruiting process. We may also use your information when analyzing our internal recruiting processes to determine (i) which recruit sources to focus on; (ii) how to improve integration and training programs for new hires with different educational backgrounds and work experience; and (iii) how to enhance our interview model to improve hiring quality. The information you provide may also be used to communicate with you about Bain events and to send you publications that we think may be of interest to you.
    
    We might share your personal data with other companies in the Bain group as well as with third parties such as recruitment service providers, background check providers and IT system providers. These Bain companies and third parties might be located in a different country than your country of residence. In particular, if you apply for a consulting role, your data will be stored in a third party database hosted in the Netherlands.
    
    We will keep your application data for up to five years. If you no longer wish for Bain to process your data or if you wish to exercise your rights, please complete [data subject request form](https://privacyportal-de.onetrust.com/webform/0ea9b6b4-9f39-441a-ad8c-05b2ae8f175c/aa3576c0-30dd-4d2e-b49b-5fdd7bfb9fe5).

    If you access the [BeyondBain](http://www.alumni.bain.com/) platform, Bain’s online alumni community, Bain will collect information about you such as your name, email, home address, previous positions, job title, company you work for, business address and any other information you choose to share on BeyondBain. To the extent that Bain already has information relevant to the creation of your Alumni profile, that information may be automatically added to your profile. However, this information will not be shared with other BeyondBain members until you have confirmed your membership. If you already were an alumni member before the launch of BeyondBain, your information will be shared in accordance to the privacy settings you had set on the previous alumni platform.
    
    You can update and amend your data at any time by logging in to BeyondBain and clicking on your profile. Please make sure your information is accurate and that you keep it up to date.
    
    Your data will be processed for purposes including managing the BeyondBain platform, populating the BeyondBain Directory, communicating Bain updates and events, conducting periodic alumni surveys as well as maintaining and sharing marketing and career development contacts.
    
    We might share your data with other companies of the Bain group and carefully selected third party service providers, including PeoplePath, Inc., which hosts and supports BeyondBain in Germany and Salesforce, Inc., which hosts our Customer Relationship Management database in Germany.
    
    Some of your information, including event registration, will also be visible to other BeyondBain community members although you can choose to make some information private. Please do not post or add information to your profile or elsewhere on BeyondBain that you would not want to be available to other members.
    
    When you register and set up your profile, your name and the other basic information you provide will be placed in the Directory. Unless you make a different selection using your profile visibility settings, your name, profile picture, current and past professional data, degrees, and social media links will be accessible to other members via your short profile. The rest of your profile information will not be shared with other members unless you update your profile visibility settings within the profile privacy settings. Once you change your visibility settings, all the information in your profile that you opt to share with registered members will be accessible to other BeyondBain members. You can manage your privacy settings at any time in your profile by clicking on your profile picture and selecting “Privacy”.
    
    BeyondBain uses cookies, which may collect personal data. For more information about how Bain uses cookies on BeyondBain and how to manage your cookie settings, please read BeyondBain’s [Cookie Policy](https://alumni.bain.com/login/cookie-policy/).
    
    Please note that BeyondBain includes Google Maps features and content, which use is subject to the current version of [Google’s Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).
    
    If you no longer wish to be a member of BeyondBain, you can request the deletion of your profile by clicking on“_Reject data privacy terms and deactivate profile_” on Settings within the BeyondBain platform or submitting your request by completing the [data subject request form](https://privacyportal-de.onetrust.com/webform/0ea9b6b4-9f39-441a-ad8c-05b2ae8f175c/aa3576c0-30dd-4d2e-b49b-5fdd7bfb9fe5). For more information about your privacy rights and how to exercise them, please refer to the “Your Rights” section below.

    Our Sites are not directed at children 16 years of age or younger. Bain, therefore, will not intentionally collect information about anyone under the age of 16, and requests that no such information be submitted to us.

    If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or how Bain handles your personal data, please complete the [data subject request form](https://privacyportal-de.onetrust.com/webform/0ea9b6b4-9f39-441a-ad8c-05b2ae8f175c/aa3576c0-30dd-4d2e-b49b-5fdd7bfb9fe5).
    
    You can also contact Bain’s Global Data Protection Officer:
    
    **Email:**  [DataPrivacy@Bain.com](mailto:DataPrivacy@Bain.com)
    
    **Post:** Global Data Protection Officer, Legal Department, Bain & Company, Inc. United Kingdom, 40 Strand, London WC2N 5RW, United Kingdom.

### Country-specific information

    **This section applies to users in the People’s Republic of China (“PRC”) (for the purposes of this Privacy Policy, excluding Hong Kong SAR, Macau SAR, and Taiwan).**
    
    * * *
    
    This section applies to you if you are resident in the PRC. The terms set out below are supplemental to, and should be read in conjunction with, the terms in this Privacy Policy. In case of any conflict or inconsistency between the Privacy Policy and this China section, this section shall prevail for residents of the PRC only.
    
    The data controllers of your personal data are Bain & Company, Inc. and Bain & Company China, Inc.
    
    Reference to personal data used in this section shall include references to sensitive personal information, where applicable, and shall have the same meanings given to those terms in relevant PRC data protection laws (as amended from time to time).
    
    **Information we collect and how we use it**
    
    Unless otherwise permitted by applicable PRC data protection laws, we will obtain consent from you if we wish to use your personal data (and sensitive personal information) for purposes other than those stated in this Privacy Policy.
    
    **Who we share your personal data with**
    
    With your consent, we may from time to time share or disclose your personal data as stated in this Privacy Policy.
    
    With your consent, we may share, transfer or store your personal data outside of the PRC, as described in this Privacy Policy, where we are satisfied that adequate levels of protection are in place to protect the integrity and security of your personal data or adequate security measures are adopted and in compliance with applicable privacy and data protection laws.
    
    **Your Rights**
    
    You may ask us to provide you with access to, or a copy of, your personal data, or correct the personal data we have about you. In certain circumstances, you may request that we delete your personal data.
    
    We will obtain your consent prior to sending you any marketing material or conducting any direct marketing activities. You may also withdraw your consent to our processing of your personal data, unsubscribe from receiving marketing information at any time, request to de-register your account, or send us complaints or inquiries about our processing of your personal data.
    
    Please complete the [data subject request form](https://privacyportal-de.onetrust.com/webform/0ea9b6b4-9f39-441a-ad8c-05b2ae8f175c/aa3576c0-30dd-4d2e-b49b-5fdd7bfb9fe5) or contact us at [DataPrivacy@Bain.com](mailto:DataPrivacy@Bain.com) if you would like to make such requests, or if you have any further questions about your rights and this Privacy Policy.
    
    **Children**
    
    Our Sites are not intended for minors under the age of 16. If you are under the age of 16 you may not use this Site. If you have concerns about your child’s privacy, or if you believe that your child may have provided us with their personal data, please contact us by completing the [data subject request form](https://privacyportal-de.onetrust.com/webform/0ea9b6b4-9f39-441a-ad8c-05b2ae8f175c/aa3576c0-30dd-4d2e-b49b-5fdd7bfb9fe5) or at [DataPrivacy@Bain.com](mailto:DataPrivacy@Bain.com). We will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible should we learn that we have collected the personal data of a child without first receiving verifiable parental consent.
    
    **Changes**
    
    Changes may be made to this Section from time to time. We recommend that you check back regularly for updates to this Section. If there are any changes to this Section which require your consent under applicable law, we will obtain your prior notified consent accordingly.

    **If you are a resident of California, you may have additional rights in relation to your personal data.**
    
    * * *
    
    As required under the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”), the categories of personal data (referred to as “personal information” in the CCPA) collected and processed by Bain, the purposes for which they are processed and the third parties such data is shared with are described in this Privacy Policy.
    
    We have not sold and do not sell your personal data within the meaning of the CCPA.
    
    If you are a resident of the State of California, you may have the right to request Bain to disclose to you:
    
    •  the categories of personal data we have collected about you;
    
    •  the categories of sources from which such personal data was collected;
    
    •  the business or commercial purpose for which we have collected your personal data;
    
    •  the third parties with whom we share your personal data; and
    
    •  the specific pieces of personal data we have collected about you.
    
    You may also have the right to request that we delete your personal data subject to the limitations of the CCPA.
    
    If you wish to exercise your rights, please submit your request using our [data subject request form](https://privacyportal-de.onetrust.com/webform/0ea9b6b4-9f39-441a-ad8c-05b2ae8f175c/aa3576c0-30dd-4d2e-b49b-5fdd7bfb9fe5). You may also submit your request by sending an email to [DataPrivacy@Bain.com](mailto:DataPrivacy@Bain.com). We may have to request additional information to verify your identity.
    
    Bain will not discriminate against you because you have exercised your rights under the CCPA.

### Definitions

### Definitions

1. The **data controller** is the person or company that, together or jointly with others, determines the purposes (why) and means (how) of the processing of personal data.

2. **Personal data** is any information that relates to an individual who is identified or identifiable, for instance by reference to a name, an identification number or an online identifier.

3. **Standard Contractual Clauses** are an agreement that can be entered into by companies for transfers of personal data outside of the European Union. They are a mechanism approved by the European Commission to ensure adequate safeguards to personal data when it is transferred outside of the European Union.

4\. **Anonymizing** means transforming data in such a way that it is no longer identifiable, i.e. the data can no longer be linked to an individual, even if combined with other information. Anonymous data is not considered "personal data".

5. **Pseudonymizing** means transforming data in such a way that it is no longer identifiable without the use of additional information. Pseudonymous data is still considered "personal data".

### Ready to talk?

I want to talk to your experts in: Select an industry Advanced Manufacturing & Services Aerospace & Defense Agribusiness Automotive Aviation Chemicals Consumer Products Energy & Natural Resources Financial Services Healthcare & Life Sciences Infrastructure, Construction & Building Products Machinery & Equipment Media & Entertainment Metals Mining Oil & Gas Paper & Packaging Private Equity Real Estate Retail Social & Public Sector Technology Telecommunications Transportation Travel & Leisure Utilities & Renewables Please select an industry from the dropdown list

We work with ambitious leaders who want to define the future, not hide from it. Together, we achieve extraordinary outcomes.

Your email  Please enter a valid email address CONTACT US

Stay ahead in a rapidly changing world. Subscribe to Bain Insights, our monthly look at the critical issues facing global businesses.

Your email address  Please enter a valid email address. \*I have read the [Privacy Policy](https://www.bain.com/about/privacy/ "Privacy Policy") and agree to its terms.

Please read and agree to the Privacy Policy.         

SUBSCRIBE

© 1996-2024 Bain & Company, Inc.

Contact Bain

#### How can we help you?
